<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:07">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>All Praise to Jesus' Hallowed Name</title>
      <title>All Praise to Thee, O Jesus Christ, O Jesus Christ, All Praise to Thee, We Praise You, Jesus at Your Birth, All Praise to Thee, Eternal Lord</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">from Walter's Geistliche Gesangbüchlein, 1524</author>
      <author type="words">German</author>
      <author type="words">Luther, Martin (1483-1546)</author>
      <author type="translate">Massie, Richard (1800-1887)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>All praise to Jesus' hallowed Name Who of virgin pure became True man for us! The angels sing As the glad news to earth they bring. Hallelujah!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Th'Eternal Father's only Son For a manger leaves His throne Disguised in our poor flesh and blood See now the everlasting Good.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>He whom the world could not inwrap Yonder lies in Mary's lap; He is become an infant small, Who by His might upholdeth all.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Th'Eternal Light, come down from heav'n, Hath to us new sunshine giv'n; It shineth in the midst of night, And maketh us the sons of light.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>The Father's Son, God ever\blest, In the world became a guest; He leads us from this vale of tears, And makes us in his kingdom heirs.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>He came to earth so mean and poor, Man to pity and restore,<br/>And make us rich in heaven above, Equal with angels through his love.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>All this He did to show His grace To our poor and sinful race;<br/>For this let Christendom adore And praise His name for evermore.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
