<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:25">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Arise possess your inheritance</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author>Author Unknown</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Rising Tabernakel"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="c1">
      <lines>Arise! and possess your inheritance<br/>This is the year of jubilee<br/>Arise! and brake the yoke of bondage<br/>For Christ has come to set the captives free</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>I was entangled with heavy chains of captivity<br/>I was bruised and mattered by sin<br/>once condemned, and sentenced to a life of bondage<br/>Oh God - there was no peace within</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>But then a sound was heard<br/>It was like the abundance of rain<br/>It said "Rejoice, you have received the atonement.<br/>Accept the pardoning work which was provided for you<br/>because - you're not of the bound woman;<br/>You're of the free</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Aren't you tired of living underprivileged<br/>Saints don't you, listen, don't you hear that sound<br/>Setting freedom to the captives<br/>restoration to the blind<br/>Setting free those who are bruiced</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Saints, empty your vessels and let him fill them with gold<br/>You are free, you are free, you are free</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>So when the creditor comes,<br/>to take away your land<br/>Show him your account<br/>settled a long ago by Calvary's Lamb<br/>I am free, I am free, I am free</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Now I can tell the world that I am free<br/>I have heard the trumpet sound Jubilee<br/>It sounded freedom from all burdens and sin<br/>The Comforter has given me peace within<br/>and "Whom The Son has set free is free indeed"</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
