<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:07">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Awake, My Soul, And With The Sun</title>
      <title>(see also 'Praise God, From Whom All Blessings Flow'</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Genevan Psalter</author>
      <author type="music">Bourgeois, Louis (1510-1561)</author>
      <author type="words">Ken, Thomas (1637-1711)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Awake, my soul, and with the sun Thy daily stage of duty run; Shake off dull sloth, and joyful rise, To pay thy morning sacrifice.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Thy precious time misspent, redeem, Each present day thy last esteem, Improve thy talent with due care; For the great day thyself prepare.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>By influence of Light divine Let thy own light to others shine. Reflect all Heaven's propitious ways In ardent love, and cheerful praise.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>In conversation be sincere; Keep conscience as the noontide clear; Think how all seeing God thy ways And all thy secret thoughts surveys.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Wake, and lift up thyself, my heart, And with the angels bear thy part, Who all night long unwearied sing High praise to the eternal King.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>All praise to Thee, Who safe has kept<br/>And hast refreshed me while I slept<br/>Grant, Lord, when I from death shall wake<br/>I may of endless light partake.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Heav'n is, dear Lord, where'er Thou art,<br/>O never then from me depart;<br/>For to my soul 'tis hell to be<br/>But for one moment void of Thee.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>Lord, I my vows to Thee renew;<br/>Disperse my sins as morning dew.<br/>Guard my first springs of thought and will,<br/>And with Thyself my spirit fill.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>Direct, control, suggest, this day,<br/>All I design, or do, or say,<br/>That all my powers, with all their might,<br/>In Thy sole glory may unite.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>I would not wake nor rise again<br/>And Heaven itself I would disdain,<br/>Wert Thou not there to be enjoyed,<br/>And I in hymns to be employed.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Praise God, from Whom all blessings flow;<br/>Praise Him, all creatures here below;<br/>Praise Him above, ye heavenly host;<br/>Praise Father, Son, and Holy Ghost.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
