<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:08">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Christ Jesus Lay In Death's Strong Bands</title>
      <title>In Death's Strong Bands</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">from Walter's Geistliche Gesangbüchlein, 1524</author>
      <author type="words">Luther, Martin (1483-1546)</author>
      <author type="translate">Massie, Richard (1800-1887)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Christ Jesus lay in death's strong bands, For our offenses given; But now at God's right hand He stands, And brings us life from Heaven. Wherefore let us joyful be, And sing to God right thankfully Loud songs of Alleluia! Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>No son of man could conquer Death, Such mischief sin had wrought us, For innocence dwelt not on earth, And therefore Death had brought us Into thralldom from of old And ever grew more strong and bold And kept us in his bondage. Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>But Jesus Christ, God's only Son, To our low state descended, The cause of Death He has undone, His power forever ended, Ruined all his right and claim And left him nothing but the name, His sting is lost forever. Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>It was a strange and dreadful strife When life and death contended; The victory remained with life; The reign of death was ended. Stripped of power, no more it reigns, An empty form alone remains Death's sting is lost forever! Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Here the true Paschal Lamb we see, Whom God so freely gave us; He died on the accursed tree So strong His love! to save us. See, His blood doth mark our door; Faith points to it, Death passes o'er, And Satan cannot harm us. Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>So let us keep the festival Where to the Lord invites us;<br/>Christ is Himself the joy of all, The Sun that warms and lights us.<br/>By His grace He doth impart Eternal sunshine to the heart;<br/>The night of sin is ended! Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Then let us feast this Easter day On the true Bread of Heaven;<br/>The Word of grace hath purged away The old and wicked leaven.<br/>Christ alone our souls will feed; He is our Meat and Drink indeed;<br/>Faith lives upon no other! Alleluia!</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
