<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:08">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Day of Wrath, O Day of Mourning</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Dykes, John Bacchus (1823-1876)</author>
      <author type="words">Thomas of Celano (13th Century)</author>
      <author type="translate">Irons, William Josiah (1812-1883)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Day of wrath, O day of mourning! See fulfilled the prophet's warning, Heav'n and earth in ashes burning.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Oh, what fear man's bosom rendeth When from Heav'n the Judge descendeth On whose sentence all dependeth!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Wondrous sound the trumpet flingeth, Through earth's sepulchers it ringeth, All before the throne it bringeth.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Death is struck and nature quaking; All creation is awaking, To its Judge an answer making.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Lo, the book, exactly worded, Wherein all hath been recorded; Thence shall judgment be awarded.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>When the Judge His seat attaineth And each hidden deed arraigneth, Nothing unavenged remaineth.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>What shall I, frail man, be pleading? Who for me be interceding When the just are mercy needing?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>King of majesty tremendous, Who dost free salvation send us, Fount of pity, then befriend us.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>Think, good Jesus, my salvation Caused Thy wondrous incarnation; Leave me not to reprobation!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>Faint and weary Thou hast sought me, On the cross of suff'ring bought me; Shall such grace be vainly brought me?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Righteous Judge, for sin's pollution<br/>Grant Thy gift of absolution<br/>Ere that day of retribution!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>Guilty, now I pour my moaning,<br/>All my shame with anguish owning:<br/>Spare, O God, Thy suppliant groaning!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v13">
      <lines>From that sinful woman shriven,<br/>From the dying thief forgiven,<br/>Thou to me a hope hast given.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v14">
      <lines>Worthless are my prayers and sighing;<br/>Yet, good Lord, in grace complying,<br/>Rescue me from fires undying.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v15">
      <lines>With Thy favored sheep, oh, place me!<br/>Nor among the goats abase me,<br/>But to Thy right hand upraise me.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v16">
      <lines>While the wicked are confounded,<br/>Doomed to flames of woe unbounded,<br/>Call me, with Thy saints surrounded.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v17">
      <lines>Low I kneel with heart submission, See, like ashes,<br/>my contrition; Help me in my last condition!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v18">
      <lines>Day of sorrow, day of weeping, When, in dust no<br/>longer sleeping, Man awakes in Thy dread keeping!</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
