<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:45:18">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Glory to Glory</title>
      <title>Created from Dust</title>
    </titles>
    <copyright>Glory to Glory lyrics © Universal Music Publishing Group</copyright>
    <authors>
      <author type="words">Lauren K. Evans / William Irvin Matthews / Richard Oscar Seibold</author>
      <author type="music">Lauren K. Evans / William Irvin Matthews / Richard Oscar Seibold</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Fonki" entry="5832"/>
    </songbooks>
    <themes>
      <theme>gospel</theme>
    </themes>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Created from dust<br/>You came and You lived among us<br/>Taken on our frame, You walked in our pain<br/>And now You're taking us higher</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>You stepped into time<br/>You laid down Your life to save us<br/>You took on our shame on the cross it was laid<br/>And now You're taking us higher</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="c1">
      <lines>We go from glory to glory to glory<br/>We'll never be the same, never be the same<br/>We go from glory to glory to glory<br/>We're forever changed, forever changed</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>You called Your friend<br/>Brought into Your endless kingdom<br/>By the blood I was made, no longer a slave<br/>And now You're taking us higher</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="c2">
      <lines>We go from glory to glory to glory<br/>We'll never be the same, never be the same<br/>We go from glory to glory to glory<br/>We're forever changed, forever changed</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="b1">
      <lines>Until we reach the day love conquers everything<br/>We'll cry an anthem singing holy, holy<br/>And when we see that day we're standing face to face<br/>We'll shout an anthem singing holy, holy</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>You took on the grave<br/>So not even death can shake us<br/>See the victor has won and Heaven has come<br/>Now You're taking us higher<br/>Now You're taking us higher</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="c3">
      <lines>We go from glory to glory to glory<br/>We'll never be the same, never be the same<br/>You take us higher and higher and higher<br/>We're forever changed, forever changed</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
