<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:09">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>His Gifts</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Brackett, Joseph (1797-1882)</author>
      <author type="words">Dumont, Brian James (1971-)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>It's His gift, this creation, all the glory we see, It's the gift laid out for Adam and for Eve, But as they turned away from His world so bright, It would plunge us deep into fear of the Light. Life, life poured out on you and me He calls us to live and His Glory to see Our Lord calls us home with Him to be in His presence living eternally!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>It's His gift, incarnation, He became us to be All the things our fallen race could never be. Our nature He would take and then justify, To the Law's demands Christ would fully comply. Life, life poured out on you and me He calls us to live and His Glory to see Our Lord calls us home with Him to be in His presence living eternally!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>It's His gift, our redemption, bought and paid in His blood All God's wrath poured out in one tremendous flood. The ransom paid for all in His act of Grace meant to bring you into His loving embrace. Life, life poured out on you and me He calls us to live and His Glory to see Our Lord calls us home with Him to be in His presence living eternally!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>It's His gift, resurrection Raised to life so that we May also with Him in glory always be. His new life is God's promise and guarantee of the gift He prepares for you and for me. Life, life poured out on you and me He calls us to live and His Glory to see Our Lord calls us home with Him to be in His presence living eternally!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>It's His gift, His ascension we await His return. Not alone, yet for His nearer presence yearn. Christ leads us to the Father and makes our home Where we'll sing together around His Throne. Life, life poured out on you and me He calls us to live and His Glory to see Our Lord calls us home with Him to be in His presence living eternally!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>It's His gift, of His Spirit poured on us in His Word<br/>Who reminds us of all Jesus taught and did.<br/>His Peace was sent to Comfort and be with us<br/>and sustain our faith in the Lord's promises.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>It's His gift, our repentance even this is from Him!<br/>When His Law and Spirit move our hearts within,<br/>They crush our vain ambition and very thoughts,<br/>drive us each to God's mercy\- His Kingdom is wrought!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>It's His gift of Baptism washed us clean in His Son<br/>placed us in His Name and took us as His own<br/>What comfort giv'n to us in this life-long trust<br/>Given faith that Christ's work is applied now to us.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>It's His Gift of His Table where He feeds us His sheep;<br/>Blest communion with our God forever sweet.<br/>His Body and His Blood poured out for us all<br/>Giv'n to heal our wounds and restore our_ soul.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>It's His Gift of eternal life spent in His embrace,<br/>To be with the Father and to sing His praise<br/>And so with God the Son who redeemed our souls<br/>With the Spirit together forever extolled.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
