<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:09">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>I Come, O Savior, To Thy Table</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">from Emskirchner Choralbuch</author>
      <author type="words">Heyder, Friedrich Christian (1677-1754)</author>
      <author type="translate">composite</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>I come, O Savior, to Thy table, For weak and weary is my soul; Thou, Bread of Life, alone art able To satisfy and make me whole: Lord, may Thy body and Thy blood Be for my soul the highest good!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Oh, grant that I in manner worthy May now approach Thy heav'nly board And, as I lowly bow before Thee, Look only unto Thee, O Lord! Lord, may Thy body and Thy blood Be for my soul the highest good!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Unworthy though I am, O Savior, Because I have a sinful heart, Yet Thou Thy lamb wilt banish never, For Thou my faithful Shepherd art: Lord, may Thy body and Thy blood Be for my soul the highest good!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Oh, let me loathe all sin forever As death and poison to my soul That I through willful sinning never May see Thy judgment take its toll! Lord, may Thy body and Thy blood Be for my soul the highest good!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Thy heart is filled with fervent yearning That sinners may salvation see Who, Lord, to Thee in faith are turning; So I, a sinner, come to Thee. Lord, may Thy body and Thy blood Be for my soul the highest good!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Weary am I and heavy laden,<br/>With sin my soul is sore opprest;<br/>Receive me graciously and gladden<br/>My heart, for I am now Thy guest.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Thou here wilt find a heart most lowly<br/>That humbly falls before Thy feet,<br/>That duly weeps o'er sin, yet solely<br/>Thy merit pleads, as it is meet.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>By faith I call Thy holy table<br/>The testament of Thy deep love;<br/>For, lo, thereby I now am able<br/>To see how love Thy heart doth move.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>What higher gift can we inherit?<br/>It is faith's bond and solid base;<br/>It is the strength of heart and spirit,<br/>The covenant of hope and grace.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>This feast is manna, wealth abounding<br/>Unto the poor, to weak ones power,<br/>To angels joy, to hell confounding,<br/>And life for me in death's dark hour.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Thy body, giv'n for me, O Savior,<br/>Thy blood which Thou for me didst shed,<br/>These are my life and strength forever,<br/>By them my hungry soul is fed.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>With Thee, Lord, I am now united;<br/>I live in Thee and Thou in me.<br/>No sorrow fills my soul, delighted<br/>It finds its only joy in Thee.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v13">
      <lines>Who can condemn me now? For surely<br/>The Lord is nigh, who justifies.<br/>No hell I fear, and thus securely<br/>With Jesus I to Heaven rise.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v14">
      <lines>Though death may threaten with disaster,<br/>It cannot rob me of my cheer;<br/>For He Who is of death the Master,<br/>With aid and comfort e'er is near.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v15">
      <lines>My heart has now become Thy dwelling, O blessèd, holy Trinity.<br/>With angels I, Thy praises telling, Shall live in joy eternally.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
