<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:09">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Jerusalem the Golden</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Ewing, Alexander C. (1830-1895)</author>
      <author type="words">Bernard of Cluny aka. Bernard of Morlaix (12th Century)</author>
      <author type="translate">Neale, John Mason (1818-1866)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Jerusalem the golden, with milk and honey blest, Beneath thy contemplation sink heart and voice oppressed. I know not, O I know not, what joys await us there, What radiancy of glory, what bliss beyond compare.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>They stand, those halls of Zion, all jubilant with song, And bright with many'an angel, and all the martyr throng; The Prince is ever in them, the daylight is serene. The pastures of the blessèd are decked in glorious sheen.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>There is the throne of David, and there, from care released, The shout of them that triumph, the song of them that feast; And they are with their Leader, who conquered in the fight, And won for them forever their gleaming robes of white.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>O sweet and blessèd country, the home of God's elect! O sweet and blessèd country, that eager hearts expect! Jesus, in mercy bring us to that dear land of rest, Who art, with God the Father, and Spirit, ever blessed.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Brief life is here our portion, brief sorrow, short lived care; The life that knows no ending, the tearless life, is there. O happy retribution! Short toil, eternal rest; For mortals and for sinners, a mansion with the blest.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>That we should look, poor wanderers, to have our home on high!<br/>That worms should seek for dwellings beyond the starry sky!<br/>And now we fight the battle, but then shall wear the crown<br/>Of full and everlasting, and passionless renown.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>And how we watch and struggle, and now we live in hope,<br/>And Zion in her anguish with Babylon must cope;<br/>But he whom now we trust in shall then be seen and known,<br/>And they that know and see Him shall have Him for their own.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>For thee, O dear, dear country, mine eyes their vigils keep;<br/>For very love, beholding, thy happy name, they weep:<br/>The mention of thy glory is unction to the breast,<br/>And medicine in sickness, and love, and life, and rest.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>O one, O only mansion! O paradise of joy!<br/>Where tears are ever banished, and smiles have no alloy;<br/>The cross is all thy splendor, the Crucified thy praise,<br/>His laud and benediction thy ransomed people raise.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>Jerusalem the glorious! Glory of the elect!<br/>O dear and future vision that eager hearts expect!<br/>E'en now by faith I see thee, e'en here thy walls discern;<br/>To thee my thoughts are kindled, and strive, and pant, and yearn.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Jerusalem, the only, that look'st from heaven below,<br/>In thee is all my glory, in me is all my woe!<br/>And though my body may not, my spirit seeks thee fain,<br/>Till flesh and earth return me to earth and flesh again.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>Jerusalem, exulting on that securest shore,<br/>I hope thee, wish thee, sing thee, and love thee evermore!<br/>I ask not for my merit: I seek not to deny<br/>My merit is destruction, a child of wrath am I.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v13">
      <lines>But yet with faith I venture and hope upon the way,<br/>For those perennial guerdons I labor night and day.<br/>The best and dearest Father Who made me, and Who saved,<br/>Bore with me in defilement, and from defilement laved.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v14">
      <lines>When in His strength I struggle, for very joy I leap;<br/>When in my sin I totter, I weep, or try to weep:<br/>And grace, sweet grace celestial, shall all its love display,<br/>And David's royal fountain purge every stain away.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v15">
      <lines>O sweet and blessèd country, shall I e'er see thy face?<br/>O sweet and blessèd country, shall I e'er win thy grace?<br/>I have the hope within me to comfort and to bless!<br/>O shall I e'er win the prize? O tell me, tell me, Yes!</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
