<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:32">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Jesus Is Alive</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author>Author Unknown</author>
    </authors>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Intro</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Verse 1<br/>For all the earth has trembled, the sun had hid its face,<br/>And all the men that walked with Him had turned and run away;<br/>They crucified the Savior  and laid Him in a tomb,<br/>The life that once brought love and hope<br/>Slipped away that afternoon.<br/>Satan gleamed with pleasure that day at Calvary,<br/>For he thought he had won a mighty victory;<br/>And, like him, all of the demons of hell began to cheer,<br/>O, but little did they know that their end was drawing near.<br/>'Cause early Sunday morning, just like Jesus said,<br/>He broke the curse of sin and death,<br/>And He rose  up from the dead;<br/>Now we have a new begin - ning,<br/>And a kingdom that has no ending<br/>Hallelu - jah! Hallelu - jah!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Chorus 1<br/>Halle - lujah! Jesus is alive,<br/>Death has lost its vict'ry and the grave has been denied;<br/>Je - sus lives forever, He's a - li - - ve, He's a - li - ve!<br/>He's the Alpha and Omega, the first and last is He,<br/>The curse of sin is broken and we have perfect liberty;<br/>The Lamb of God has risen,<br/>He's a - li - - ve, He's a - li - ve!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Verse 2<br/>He is the author and the finisher of our faith,<br/>The stone they threw away  is the Cornerstone today;<br/>Death has no more victory and the grave has no more sting.<br/>Hallelujah! Hallelujah!<br/>Wonderful Counselor, a Mighty God is He;<br/>The everlasting Father, He's the precious Prince of Peace.<br/>He's the Word that lasts forever,<br/>He's a - li - - ve, He's a - li - ve!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Chorus 2<br/>Halle - lujah! Jesus is alive,<br/>Death has lost its vict'ry and the grave has been denied;<br/>Je - sus lives forever, He's a - li - - ve, He's a - li - - ve!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Ending<br/>He's a - live.  He's a - live.<br/>Halle - lujah! Je - sus is a - live!</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
