<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:10">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Lord, Thee I Love with All My Heart</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">from Strassburg</author>
      <author type="words">Schalling, Martin (1532-1608)</author>
      <author type="translate">Winkworth, Catherine (1827-1878)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Lord, Thee I love with all my heart; I pray Thee, ne'er from me depart; With tender mercy cheer me. Earth has no pleasure I would share, Yea, Heav'n itself were void and bare If Thou, Lord, wert not near me. And should my heart for sorrow break, My trust in Thee can nothing shake. Thou art the portion I have sought; Thy precious blood my soul has bought. Lord Jesus Christ, My God and Lord, my God and Lord, Forsake me not! I trust Thy Word.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Yea, Lord, 'twas Thy rich bounty gave My body, soul, and all I have In this poor life of labor. Lord, grant that I in every place May glorify Thy lavish grace And serve and help my neighbor. Let no false doctrine me beguile, Let Satan not my soul defile. Give strength and patience unto me To bear my cross and follow Thee. Lord Jesus Christ, My God and Lord, my God and Lord, In death Thy comfort still afford.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Lord, let at last Thine angels come, To Abr'am's bosom bear me home, That I may die unfearing; And in its narrow chamber keep My body safe in peaceful sleep Until Thy reappearing. And then from death awaken me, That these mine eyes with joy may see, O Son of God, Thy glorious face, My Savior and my fount of grace. Lord Jesus Christ, My prayer attend, my prayer attend, And I will praise Thee without end!</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
