<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:13">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Lord God, Thy Praise We Sing</title>
      <title>Te Deum Laudamus</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Latin</author>
      <author type="words">Luther, Martin (1483-1546)</author>
      <author type="music">Luther, Martin (1483-1546)</author>
      <author type="translate">Massie, Richard (1800-1887)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Lord God, Thy praise we sing; Father in eternity, Lord God, our thanks we bring; Angels all and heav'nly host All the world worships Thee. Of Thy glory loudly boast; Both Cherubim and Seraphim Holy art Thou, our God! Sing ever with loud voice this hymn: Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! Holy art Thou, our God! Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! Thy majesty and godly might Fill the earth and all the realms of light. The twelve apostles join in song With the dear prophets' goodly throng Thee, Father, on Thy highest throne, Thy worthy, true, and well belov'd Son, The Comforter, ev'n the Holy Ghost, Whereof she makes her constant boast. Thee King of all glory, Christ, we own, Th'eternal Father's eternal Son. To save mankind Thou hast not, Lord, The Virgin Mary's womb abhorred; Thy servants help whom Thou, O God, Hast ransomed with that precious blood; Grant that we share the heav'nly rest With the happy saints eternally blest. Help us, O Lord, from age to age, And bless Thy chosen heritage. Nourish and keep them by Thy pow'r, And lift them up for evermore. Lord God, we praise Thee day by day, And sanctify Thy Name always. Keep us this day, and at all times, From secret sins and open crimes; In Thee, Lord, have we put our trust; O never let our hope be lost! Amen. Amen.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Lord God, Thy praise we sing; Father in eternity, Lord God, our thanks we bring; Angels all and heav'nly host All the world worships Thee. Of Thy glory loudly boast; Both Cherubim and Seraphim Holy art Thou, our God! Sing ever with loud voice this hymn: Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! Holy art Thou, our God! Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! The martyrs' noble army raise Their voice to Thee in hymns of praise. Thee, Father, on Thy highest throne, Thy worthy, true, and well belov'd Son, The Comforter, ev'n the Holy Ghost, Whereof she makes her constant boast. Thee King of all glory, Christ, we own, Th'eternal Father's eternal Son. Thou over camest death's sharp sting, Believers unto heav'n to bring; Thy servants help whom Thou, O God, Hast ransomed with that precious blood; Grant that we share the heav'nly rest With the happy saints eternally blest. Help us, O Lord, from age to age, And bless Thy chosen heritage. Nourish and keep them by Thy pow'r, And lift them up for evermore. Lord God, we praise Thee day by day, And sanctify Thy Name always. Keep us this day, and at all times, From secret sins and open crimes; In Thee, Lord, have we put our trust; O never let our hope be lost! Amen. Amen.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Lord God, Thy praise we sing; Father in eternity, Lord God, our thanks we bring; Angels all and heav'nly host All the world worships Thee. Of Thy glory loudly boast; Both Cherubim and Seraphim Holy art Thou, our God! Sing ever with loud voice this hymn: Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! Holy art Thou, our God! Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! The universal Church doth Thee Throughout the world confess to be Thee, Father, on Thy highest throne, Thy worthy, true, and well belov'd Son, The Comforter, ev'n the Holy Ghost, Whereof she makes her constant boast. Thee King of all glory, Christ, we own, Th'eternal Father's eternal Son. At God's right hand Thou sittest, clad In th'glory with the Father had; Thy servants help whom Thou, O God, Hast ransomed with that precious blood; Grant that we share the heav'nly rest With the happy saints eternally blest. Help us, O Lord, from age to age, And bless Thy chosen heritage. Nourish and keep them by Thy pow'r, And lift them up for evermore. Lord God, we praise Thee day by day, And sanctify Thy Name always. Keep us this day, and at all times, From secret sins and open crimes; In Thee, Lord, have we put our trust; O never let our hope be lost! Amen. Amen.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Lord God, Thy praise we sing; Father in eternity, Lord God, our thanks we bring; Angels all and heav'nly host All the world worships Thee. Of Thy glory loudly boast; Both Cherubim and Seraphim Holy art Thou, our God! Sing ever with loud voice this hymn: Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! Holy art Thou, our God! Holy art Thou, our God, the Lord of Sabaoth! The universal Church doth Thee Throughout the world confess to be Thee, Father, on Thy highest throne, Thy worthy, true, and well belov'd Son, The Comforter, ev'n the Holy Ghost, Whereof she makes her constant boast. Thee King of all glory, Christ, we own, Th'eternal Father's eternal Son. Thou shalt in glory come again, To judge both dead and living men. Thy servants help whom Thou, O God, Hast ransomed with that precious blood; Grant that we share the heav'nly rest With the happy saints eternally blest. Help us, O Lord, from age to age, And bless Thy chosen heritage. Nourish and keep them by Thy pow'r, And lift them up for evermore. Lord God, we praise Thee day by day, And sanctify Thy Name always. Keep us this day, and at all times, From secret sins and open crimes; In Thee, Lord, have we put our trust; O never let our hope be lost! Amen. Amen.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
