<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:10">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>My Neighbor</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Tallis, Thomas (1505-1585)</author>
      <author type="words">Fleischmann, John G. (1960-)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Unclean and battered, torn by sin, By things I do, my thoughts within, I lie there bloodied on life's road with death and sin my only load.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Across that road the world passed by turning a deaf ear to my cry, No help to give, they could not save and so they left me for my grave.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>And, what of me, when I saw need? Did I my Savior's bidding heed? Too often on the other side I've walked away because of pride.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Sin bleeds from me and stops my breath, in Adam all I know is death; My works are rags, my offerings vain, From dust I came in dust remain.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>But in my need my Savior died, Not passing on the other side. Rebreathed His Spirit in my dust, bound up my wounds, declared me just.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Now safe within His Church I'm free; Blood, Water, Spirit plead for me,<br/>The Ark of God, the Inn of Grace Where I behold my Father's face.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>May I in Christ my neighbor know Binding his wounds serves Christ below.<br/>Your love for him make plain through me, that he may, too, your Glory see.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>You loved me when I could not love, For my sin barred me from above.<br/>In Christ my love is now set free, O praise and bless the Trinity.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
