<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2021-09-05T08:10:13">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Onward Christian Soldiers</title>
    </titles>
    <verseOrder>v1 c1 v2 c1 v3 c1 v4 c1 v5 c1</verseOrder>
    <authors>
      <author>Sabine Baring-Gould</author>
    </authors>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Onward christian soldiers,<br/>Marching as to war,<br/>With the cross of Jesus <br/>Going on before! <br/>Christ, the royal Master, <br/>Leads against the foe; <br/>Forward into battle, <br/>See, His banners go!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="c1">
      <lines>Onward, Christian soldiers, <br/>Marching as to war, <br/>With the cross of Jesus <br/>Going on before.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>At the name of Jesus <br/>Satan’s host doth flee; <br/>On then, Christian soldiers, <br/>On to victory! <br/>Hell’s foundations quiver <br/>At the shout of praise; <br/>Brothers, lift your voices; <br/>Loud your anthems raise:</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Like a mighty army <br/>Moves the church of God: <br/>Brothers we are treading <br/>Where the saints have trod. <br/>We are not divided,<br/>All one body we, <br/>One in hope and doctrine, <br/>One in charity.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Crowns and thrones may perish, <br/>Kingdoms rise and wane, <br/>But the church of Jesus <br/>Constant will remain; <br/>Gates of hell can never <br/>’Gainst that church prevail; <br/>We have Christ’s own promise, <br/>And that cannot fail:</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Onward, then, ye people! <br/>Join our happy throng; <br/>Blend with ours your voices <br/>In the triumph-song: <br/>Glory, laud, and honour <br/>Unto Christ the King! <br/>This through countless ages <br/>Men and angels sing:</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
