<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:11">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Rejoice, My Heart, Be Glad and Sing</title>
      <title>O Lord I Sing with Lips and Heart</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">König, Johann Balthasar (1691-1758)</author>
      <author type="words">Gerhardt, Paul (1607-1676)</author>
      <author type="translate">composite</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Rejoice, my heart, be glad and sing, A cheerful trust maintain; For God, the Source of everything, Thy Portion shall remain.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>He is thy Treasure, He thy Joy, Thy Life and Light and Lord, Thy Counselor when doubts annoy, Thy Shield and great Reward.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Why spend the day in blank despair, In restless thought the night? On thy Creator cast thy care; He makes thy burdens light.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Did not His love and truth and pow'r Watch o'er thy childhood day? Has He not oft in threat'ning hour Turned dreaded ills away?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>His wisdom never plans in vain, Ne'er falters or mistakes; All that His counsels did ordain A happy ending makes.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Upon thy lips, then, lay thy hand<br/>And trust His guiding love;<br/>Then like a rock thy peace shall stand<br/>Here and in heav'n above.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>O Lord I sing with lips and heart,<br/>Joy of my soul, to Thee:<br/>To Earth Thy knowledge I impart,<br/>As it is known to me.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>Thou art the Fount of grace, I know,<br/>And Spring so full and free,<br/>Whence saving health and goodness flow<br/>Each day so bounteously.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>For what have all that live and move<br/>Through this wide world below<br/>That does not from Thy bounteous love,<br/>O Heav'nly Father flow?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>Who built the lofty firmament?<br/>Who spread th'expanse of blue?<br/>By whom are to our pastures sent<br/>Refreshing rain and dew?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Who warmeth us in cold and frost?<br/>Who shields us from the wind?<br/>Who orders it that oil and must<br/>We in their season find?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>Who is it life and health bestows?<br/>Who keeps us with His hand<br/>In golden peace, wards off war's woes<br/>From our dear native land?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v13">
      <lines>O Lord of this and all our store<br/>Thou art the author blest;<br/>Thou keepest watch before our door,<br/>While we securely rest.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v14">
      <lines>Thou feedest us from year to year,<br/>And constant dost abide;<br/>With ready help in time of fear,<br/>Thou standest at our side.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v15">
      <lines>He ever will with patience chide,<br/>His rod falls gently down,<br/>And all thy sins He casts aside<br/>And in the sea doth drown.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v16">
      <lines>When silent woe thy bosom rends,<br/>His pity sees thy grief,<br/>Supplies what to His glory tends<br/>And to thine own relief.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v17">
      <lines>He knows how oft a Christian weeps<br/>And why his tears now fall;<br/>And in the book His mercy keeps<br/>These things are noted all.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v18">
      <lines>Our deepest needs dost Thou supply,<br/>Thou giv'st what lasts for aye.<br/>Thou lead'st us to our home on high,<br/>When hence we pass away.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
