<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2021-09-05T08:10:14">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>The God of Abraham Praise</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author>Thomas Olivers</author>
    </authors>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>The God of Abraham praise,<br/>Who reigns enthroned above,<br/>Ancient of everlasting days, and God of love.<br/>Jehovah! Great I AM!<br/>By earth and heaven confessed;<br/>I bow and bless the sacred name forever blessed.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>The God of Abraham praise,<br/>At whose supreme command<br/>From earth I rise, and seek the joys at His right hand.<br/>I all on earth forsake --<br/>Its wisdom, fame, and power --<br/>And Him my only portion make, my shield and tower.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>The God of Abraham praise,<br/>Whose all-sufficient grace<br/>Shall guide me all my happy days in all my ways.<br/>He calls a worm His friend,<br/>He calls Himself my God;<br/>And He shall save me to the end through Jesu’s blood.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>He by Himself hath sworn,<br/>I on His oath depend:<br/>I shall, on eagles’ wings upborne, to heaven ascend;<br/>I shall behold His face,<br/>I shall His power adore,<br/>And sing the wonders of His grace forever more.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>There dwells the Lord our King,<br/>The Lord our Righteousness,<br/>Triumphant o’er the world and sin, the Prince of Peace;<br/>On Zion’s sacred height<br/>His kingdom still maintains,<br/>And glorious with His saints in light forever reigns.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>The God who reigns on high<br/>The great archangels sing;<br/>And, holy, holy, holy, cry, Almighty King.<br/>Who was and is the same,<br/>And ever more shall be;<br/>Jehovah, Father, Great I AM, we worship Thee.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Before the Saviour’s face<br/>The ransomed nations bow;<br/>O’erwhelmed at His almighty grace, forever new:<br/>He shows His prints of love,<br/>They kindle to a flame,<br/>And sound through all the worlds above the slaughtered Lamb.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>The whole triumphant host<br/>Give thanks to God on high;<br/>Hail, Father, Son, and Holy Ghost! They ever cry.<br/>Hail, Abraham’s God, and mine!<br/>I join the heavenly lays;  All might and majesty <br/>are Thine, and endless praise.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
