<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:12">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>The God of Abraham Praise</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Hebrew</author>
      <author type="words">ben Judah, Daniel (circa 1400)</author>
      <author type="translate">Olivers, Thomas (1725-1799)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>The God of Abr'ham praise, Who reigns enthroned above; Ancient of everlasting days, and God of Love; Jehovah, great I AM! by earth and Heav'n confessed; I bow and bless the sacred Name forever blessed.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>The God of Abr'ham praise, at Whose supreme command From earth I rise and seek the joys at His right hand; I all on earth forsake, its wisdom, fame, and pow'r; And Him my only Portion make, my Shield and Tow'r.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>The God of Abr'ham praise, Whose all sufficient grace Shall guide me all my happy days, in all my ways. He calls a worm His friend, He calls Himself my God! And He shall save me to the end, thro' Jesus' blood.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>He by Himself has sworn; I on His oath depend, I shall, on eagle wings upborne, to Heav'n ascend. I shall behold His face; I shall His pow'r adore, And sing the wonders of His grace forevermore.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Tho' nature's strength decay, and earth and hell withstand, To Canaan's bounds I urge my way, at His command. The wat'ry deep I pass, with Jesus in my view; And thro' the howling wilderness my way pursue.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>The goodly land I see, with peace and plenty bless'd;<br/>A land of sacred liberty, and endless rest.<br/>There milk and honey flow, and oil and wine abound,<br/>And trees of life forever grow with mercy crowned.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>There dwells the Lord our King, the Lord our righteousness,<br/>Triumphant o'er the world and sin, the Prince of peace;<br/>On Sion's sacred height His kingdom still maintains,<br/>And glorious with His saints in light forever reigns.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>He keeps His own secure, He guards them by His side,<br/>Arrays in garments, white and pure, His spotless bride:<br/>With streams of sacred bliss, with groves of living joys -<br/>With all the fruits of Paradise, He still supplies.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>Before the great Three-One they all exulting stand;<br/>And tell the wonders He hath done, through all their land:<br/>The list'ning spheres attend, and swell the growing fame;<br/>And sing, in songs which never end, the wondrous Name.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>The God Who reigns on high the great archangels sing,<br/>And "Holy, holy, holy!" cry, "Almighty King!<br/>Who was, and is, the same, and evermore shall be:<br/>Jehovah - Father - great I AM, we worship Thee!"</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Before the Savior's face the ransomed nations bow;<br/>O'erwhelmed at His almighty grace, forever new:<br/>He shows His prints of love - they kindle to a flame!<br/>And sound thro' all the worlds above the slaughtered Lamb.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>The whole triumphant host give thanks to God on high;<br/>"Hail, Father, Son, and Holy Ghost," they ever cry.<br/>Hail, Abraham's God, and mine! (I join the heav'nly lays,)<br/>All might and majesty are Thine, and endless praise.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
