<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:12">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>The Cloud Received Christ From Their Sight</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Gläser, Carl Gotthelf (1784-1829)</author>
      <author type="words">Dumont, Brian James (1971-)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>The cloud received Christ from their sight. They stood, their mouths agape. Reminded of the things He taught His people still do wait.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>The cloud kept safe God's people as Through the dry sea they trod, And led them through the wilderness; They truly walked with God!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>On Sinai's height the cloud did rest To make a home below. The Ark first then His written Word His presence now would show.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Appearing on the mercy seat within the inmost place, the Temple showed God's promises to save our fallen race.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>On mountain high Christ's face did shine like sun, a blazing light. The cloud once more appeared on earth a truly fearful sight.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>While here in flesh You taught us, Lord<br/>The object sure and right:<br/>To see our Father's glory bright,<br/>To have eternal life.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>A goal beyond our reach You've shown;<br/>We cannot pay the price.<br/>No work of ours atones for sin,<br/>We cannot set things right.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>You are the Truth, You are the Way<br/>for us to see His face.<br/>You died for us a sinner's death<br/>abandoned in our place.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>On Easter day, Lord, You were raised<br/>Firstfruits of our new Life;<br/>And in the cloud we see the day<br/>When joy will end all strife.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>We wait to see the cloud's return<br/>To be with us below,<br/>When You fulfill Your promises<br/>To bring us to Your home.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>And though we wait to see You now<br/>We know that You are near.<br/>Your promises to build our faith<br/>Are stronger than our fear.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>You give us faith by Your strong Word<br/>In water, wine, and bread.<br/>The Spirit works through earthly means,<br/>in pastures green we're fed.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
