<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:12">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>To Jordan Came Our Lord, The Christ</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Walther, Johann (1496-1570)</author>
      <author type="words">Luther, Martin (1483-1546)</author>
      <author type="translate">Massie, Richard (1800-1887)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>To Jordan came our Lord the Christ, To do God's pleasure willing, And there was by Saint John baptized, All righteousness fulfilling; There did He consecrate a bath To wash away transgression, And quench the bitterness of death By His own blood and passion; He would a new life give us.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>So hear ye all, and well perceive What God doth call baptism, And what a Christian should believe Who error shuns and schism: That we should water use, the Lord Declareth it His pleasure; Not simple water, but the Word And Spirit without measure; He is the true Baptizer.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>To show us this, He hath His Word With signs and symbols given; On Jordan's banks was plainly heard The Father's voice from Heaven: "This is My well\beloved Son, In whom My soul delighteth; Hear Him." Yea, hear Him every one Whom He Himself inviteth, Hear and obey His teaching.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>In tender manhood Jesus straight To holy Jordan wendeth; The Holy Ghost from Heaven's gate In dovelike shape descendeth; That thus the truth be not denied, Nor should our faith e'er waver, That the Three Persons all preside, At baptism's holy laver, And dwell with the believer.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Thus Jesus His disciples sent: Go teach ye every nation, That lost in sin they must repent; And flee from condemnation: He that believes and is baptized, Obtains a mighty blessing; A newborn man, no more he dies, Eternal life possessing, A joyful heir of Heaven.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>Who in this mercy hath not faith, Nor aught therein discerneth,<br/>Is yet in sin, condemned to death, And fire that ever burneth;<br/>His holiness avails him not, Nor aught which he is doing;<br/>His inborn sin brings all to naught, And maketh sure his ruin;<br/>Himself he cannot succor.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>The eye of sense alone is dim, And nothing sees but water;<br/>Faith sees Christ Jesus, and in Him The Lamb ordained for slaughter;<br/>She sees the cleansing fountain red With the dear blood of Jesus,<br/>Which from the sins inherited From fallen Adam frees us,<br/>And from our own misdoings.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
