<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:13">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Yet Before We See Your Plans</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">Moore, William (19th Century)</author>
      <author type="music">from Columbian Harmony</author>
      <author type="words">Dumont, Brian James (1971-)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Yet before we see Your plans, Lord; While the path is still unknown Bless us Lord to shout Your praises, May Your work through us be shown. Give us faith to trust Your mercy, Make us confident to be Called and holy as Your Church who Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Marching round the walls of Jer'cho Went Your trumpeted parade. Celebrating Your great triumph E'en before it was displayed. Give us faith to trust Your mercy, Make us confident to be Called and holy as Your Church who Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>With four armies bearing on them King Jehoshaphat would send First the band to sing your praises, Thus Your glory to extend. Give us faith to trust Your mercy, Make us confident to be Called and holy as Your Church who Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>On that night before He died The Lord to You would raise a hymn He would sing Your praise and mercy E'en before the battle grim. Give us faith to trust Your mercy, Make us confident to be Called and holy as Your Church who Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>And we lowly helpless few harassed and fettered by our sin More than conquerors in Christ for He did our salvation win. Give us faith to trust Your mercy, Make us confident to be Called and holy as Your Church who Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>All around us Lord we see a<br/>World that spins and spirals down.<br/>While our hindered human eyes can't<br/>See You turning us around.<br/>Give us faith to trust Your mercy,<br/>Make us confident to be<br/>Called and holy as Your Church who<br/>Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>In our lives and times so broken<br/>By our sin and willful pride<br/>Or just with uncertainty, Your<br/>Plans You often seem to hide,<br/>Give us faith to trust Your mercy,<br/>Make us confident to be<br/>Called and holy as Your Church who<br/>Shout and sing Your victory.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
