<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:05">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>You People Who Now Are Baptized</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author type="music">from Klug's Geistliche Lieder, Wittenberg, 1533</author>
      <author type="words">Gerhardt, Paul (1607-1676)</author>
      <author type="translate">Dumont, Brian James (1971-)</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Open Hymnal"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>You people who now are baptized God's gracious love surrounds you. By Christ's Name you're now recognized; Ponder what happened to you: Whose work was it which fashioned you, Whose inborn nature that He slew, When you first gained His promise?</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>Before held in your mother's arm, From your time of conception, Quite hostile to the Law's alarms\Let there be no deception. A sinner born of sinner's seed; Still God Himself for you would bleed, He took on flesh to save you.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Your soul and body turned within, Sin filled you like a poison. Concern for neighbor paperthin; God's love was simply foreign. Then raised by God the Lord of Life To glow in His eternal Light Your robe of white is gleaming.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>The majesty that terrifies Was all God's presence brought you. Your fault you could not rectify; Anxiety consumed you. A slave of sin and Satan held Trapped in a prison bound for hell Death was your only future.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>Then washed clean in this holy flood, The water of Baptism; Instilled faith in Christ's holy blood Brought to the Father's Kingdom, Your heart rebuilt within your breast, New nature filled with righteousness, Your every sin forgiven!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>It washes all your sins away<br/>And makes you pure and holy.<br/>Hell's hold on you was lost that day,<br/>God's freedom for the lowly.<br/>You are now truly God's dear child<br/>An heir of heaven undefiled<br/>With crown to cast before Him.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Your nature lost in Adam's fall,<br/>Corrupt through generations,<br/>Refreshed now in the waterfall-<br/>A perfect new creation!<br/>The death of death before your eyes:<br/>God's power must be recognized.<br/>Hell's demons lie defeated!</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v8">
      <lines>Now we can gladly draw to Christ<br/>And boldly ask His blessing<br/>Because of Jesus' sacrifice,<br/>Our sins upon Him pressing.<br/>The Father looks on us and sees<br/>Christ's holiness and His good deeds:<br/>White robes giv'n by His merit.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v9">
      <lines>This holy bath ... What pow'r displays!<br/>What wondrous grace-filled cleansing;<br/>None on their own can e'er appraise<br/>The value of their raising.<br/>The Word of God in simple form<br/>Can calm the tempest and the storm.<br/>It brings peace to your spirit.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v10">
      <lines>Plain water cannot wash our sin<br/>Nor clean our inward spirit,<br/>But water with God's promise can<br/>Bring all the Father wills it.<br/>The water that floods over you<br/>From God's command has strength imbued.<br/>His Name is placed upon you.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v11">
      <lines>Too precious to repay somehow,<br/>Just grateful thanks we offer.<br/>Christ's work has been delivered now<br/>To you through Word and water.<br/>Nothing but Christ's atoning work<br/>In you could kill death's ugly smirk<br/>You're now refreshed and holy.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v12">
      <lines>Now gladly live as God's dear child<br/>Proclaim to all His Gospel<br/>Shine to the world; be undefiled...<br/>A beacon to all people.<br/>Till called home to eternal joy<br/>With new song that we'll all employ<br/>To cast our crowns before Him.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
