<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<song xmlns="http://openlyrics.info/namespace/2009/song" version="0.8" createdIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedIn="OpenLP 2.4.6" modifiedDate="2022-04-17T08:46:20">
  <properties>
    <titles>
      <title>Your day's getting close - o Lord, God Almighty</title>
    </titles>
    <authors>
      <author>Author Unknown</author>
    </authors>
    <songbooks>
      <songbook name="Fonki" entry="1576"/>
    </songbooks>
  </properties>
  <lyrics>
    <verse name="v1">
      <lines>Your day's getting close - o Lord, God Almighty,<br/>When all nations will come before You,<br/>2X: With trump of archangels and angel shouting<br/>You will gather all nations, who trust onto You.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v2">
      <lines>As on days before flood people ate, drank, got married -<br/>Didn't think that the end to their life'll ever come -<br/>2X: But God opened sky's windows, and pour rain from heaven,<br/>Killing everything that had a breath in their lungs.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v3">
      <lines>Like Sodom and Gomorra, having bad passion,<br/>Who fomented shameful fire among themselves,<br/>2X: Refusing the law of God's ultimate power -<br/>Tasted God's wrath themselves at this terrible day.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v4">
      <lines>Two workers at that day will work at the same field -<br/>One of them would be carried to Jesus by clouds,<br/>2X: But it will be too late for the other to repent -<br/>He deserved to be fairly punished by God.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v5">
      <lines>In the blink of the eye Christ will return here<br/>For the people, who did stay loyal to Him,<br/>2X: And He'll say: «loyal slave, enter your Master's kingdom<br/>You are worthy to be celebrating with Me»</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v6">
      <lines>After some time of rest people'll raise up for torments,<br/>To be judged by the Christ with the rest of alive,<br/>2X: Even those, who are brave will shout out fear, seeing Great God,<br/>All the people will cry seeing Fearsome Lord Christ.</lines>
    </verse>
    <verse name="v7">
      <lines>Your day's getting close - o Lord, God Almighty,<br/>When all nations will come before You,<br/>2X: With trump of archangels and angel shouting<br/>You will gather all nations, who trust onto You.</lines>
    </verse>
  </lyrics>
</song>
